# SAMUEL RAOUL DJIANI

2328 Sherry Circle, Apt L3, Milledgeville, GA 31061 | (H) 4784531802 | (C) 575 650 7236 | djiani87@nmsu.edu

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-raoul-djiani-0a78b1a2

### **Professional Summary**

A results-driven, customer-focused, Software Engineer and Front-end/back-end Web developer who can think "out of the box". Advance knowledge in Java, C/C++, python, and web responsive designed with database analysis and management. Experienced in full project life cycle from design to implementation to integration.

#### **Skills**

- Java, C/C++, Python, R, Matlab
- html5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, AJax, Node.js, Express, Passport
- Embedded System: Arduino, Raspberry Pi (IoT certification)
- Glut(OpenGL), OpenCV, Mayavi
- Mongodb, MySQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, Oracle
- API design knowledge

- Object-Oriented Analysis, Design and Development / Relational Database Systems
- Managing and supporting multiple projects
- Implementing software development life cycle policies and procedures
- Highly adaptable in quickly changing technical environments with very strong organizational and analytical skills

## **Work History**

#### **Computational Scientist**

01/2015 to 05/2017

New Mexico State University - Las Cruces, New Mexico, United States

- Designing, Developing, and maintaining INVERSION SOFTCDI package to solve the phase problem in X-ray Coherence Diffraction Imaging.
- 2D/3D Image prepossessing and data visualization
- Identification and tracking of crystals' defects within the reconstructed particles
- Built, tested, and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.

**Teacher Assistant** 08/2014 to 12/2016

New Mexico State University – Las Cruces, New Mexico

 CS 110(introduction to computer science), CS 272(object oriented programming), CS 273(Machine Programming and Organization), CS 278 (Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science);

- Grading homework and lab assignments
- Presenting structured learning labs where students could ask questions regarding Java, C/C++, object oriented, assembly language
- Preparing structured teaching guides pertaining to chapter material that complemented the professor's lecture.

#### **Internship-Software Programmer**

05/2010 to 07/2010

Koosery technology – Douala, Cameroon

- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems
- Maintained existing applications, designed, and delivered new applications.
- Analyzed and designed relational databases using MySQL

#### **Education**

Master of Science: Computer Science

May 2017

New Mexico State University - las Cruces

Master Project Inverse SoftCDI Software package to solve the inverse scattering Problem in X-ray Coherence Diffraction **Imaging** 

Major Courses took Intro. to Smart Grids; Data Mining; Databases Management II; Computer architecture II; Artificial Intelligence Iⅈ intro. to robotics; Programming Languages structures; Analysis of Algorithms; Automata, Languages, Computability.

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Sept 2011

University of Douala - Douala, Cameroon

Major courses took: Software Development, Databases I, Artificial Intelligence I, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Algebra.

#### Certification

#### **Certification: Full Stack Web Development**

In Progress

Thinkful BootCamp - Atlanta, GA

- Coursework in Web Design and Development
- Asynchronous Web Apps,
- Server-side Programming with JavaScript

#### **Awards**

Outstanding Teaching Assistant Spring 2016

## **Spoken Language**

English(Advanced) and French(native)